# Gasem K. Gasem

Student

### Contact

**Address** 

520 Farmers Market Way Apt 8201 Dallas, TX, 75201

**Phone** (405) 269-6487

**E-mail**Gasemjobs@gmail.com

#### **Skills**

Written/Verbal Communication

Consulting Skills/Strategies

Project Management

Computer Programming Fundamentals and Logic

Python

Assembly (Intel x86)

HTML5/CSS

Microsoft Office Suite

**General Computer Proficiency** 

Hardware and software installation

Name Symmetry

Versatile and self-motivated Mechanical/Fire-Safety Engineer looking for a position in Sales Engineering, or a related role. I offer 2 years of experience in engineering and risk consultation; aiding clients across various industries improve site risk exposure. I have strong critical thinking/problem-solving skills paired with excellent written and verbal communication. This allows me to offer solutions, while clearly conveying said solutions to individuals with a variety of business and technical backgrounds. This in conjunction with a strong interpersonal intuition, I am skilled in persuasion towards collaboration.

## **Work History**

# 2018-01 - Consultant Engineer

FM Global, Frisco, TX

- Managed ongoing construction projects ensuring FM Global standards are met in terms of construction, automatic fire protection, processes, natural hazards, etc.
- Worked with various Fortune 1000 companies performing engineering-based risk improvement inspections and consultation.
- Referenced and applied engineering and industry standards to improve client risk exposure.
- Regularly communicated and followed-up with clients on a high and low level with the intent to implement recommendations.
- Reviewed construction documents and schematics to ensure adequate design criteria for new and ongoing projects.

# 2020-09 - Treasury Analyst - Contract

Empire Petroleum, Dallas, TX

- Oversaw the entering and execution of wires and ACH transfers across multiple internal and external accounts.
- Ensured adequate accounting records were written and filed for auditing purposes.
- Supported internal and external audit requests from other finance departments.
- Maintained a standard of compliance with internal controls, policies, and procedures.

### **Education**

2013-01 -

2017-12

2020-11

2020-09 - Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Current

Cracen State University Computing OR

Oregon State University - Corvallis, OR

Bachelor of Science: Mechanical Engineering
Oklahoma State University - Stillwater, OK